

# **SOUFIANE DAKIR**

**IT Career Coach** 

### **PROFIL**

IT career coach specializing in IT career transformations. Notable successes in effectively placing graduates, maximizing satisfaction for learners and candidates. Builder of strategic partnerships to enhance professional opportunities. Provides personalized coaching to guide IT professionals towards success in an ever-evolving industry.

#### CONTACT

Soufiane.dakir@outlook.com

06 63 33 59 79

Casablanca, Maroc

www.linkedin.com/in/soufiane-dakir

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

**Programming:** HTML, CSS, JS, Java, Python...

Database: SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle...

System: Windows Server, Linux, Cisco...

**Network:** Cisco Networking, Switching, Routing and Security, AWS, Azure...

Project Management: Scrum, ITIL, JIRA...

Big Data: Hadoop, Spark, Hive...

Analysis: Excel, Power BI, QlikView...

# **LANGUAGES**

Arabic: Native

French: Bilingual English: Professional

Chinese: Intermediary

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Management Information Specialist | University-365

Dec.2019 – Jun.2023 | Tianjin, China (3 years 10 months)

- Conduct technical courses on AWS Cloud Foundations, AWS Machine Learning Foundations, Windows Server, Linux, Cisco, ITIL, Scrum, and Python.
- Coordinate academic initiatives with university partners.
- Develop marketing strategies to promote bilateral exchanges including China, Europe, and Africa.

# IT Strategy & Business Junior Analyst | CRM Factory

Mar.2018 - Oct.2018 | Beijing, China (8 months)

- Analyze and perform client requirements.
- Coordinate project management activities and resources
- IT Strategy, Design and Continual Service Improvement
- Develop royalty marketing strategy with partners.

#### IT Delivery | INTELCIA Group

Mar.2015 – Aug.2015 | Casablanca, Morocco (6 months)

- Elaborate IT deliveries of customer projects
- Analyze technical problems.
- Manage technical support.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Master's degree – Computer Science & Information Technology

SUPINFO International University | Tianjin/Beijing - China 2017 – 2019

### Bachelor – Computer Science & Information Technology

SUPINFO International University | Casablanca, Morocco 2016 – 2017

#### **Bachelor of Applied Science – Applied Mathematics**

Hassan 2 University of Science | Casablanca, Morocco 2012 – 2016

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Big Data: Analysis of Big Data & Hadoop Administration

Data Warehouse: Cloud-based Data Warehousing solutions

**AWS**: Academy Cloud Foundations /

Academy Machine Learning Foundations

**Google**: Digital Marketing Fundamentals